## Sintayehu Mekonnen

sintemite@gmail.com

https://sintu.ga

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sintayehu-mekonnen-35b88716a/ (404) 935-2192

## **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

I am an energetic, well-trained for Computer Science basic skills and proven skills in web development including knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, JavaScript library, and frameworks. Extensive experience for Web Developer who knows how to create, design, and modify web content.

I am a results-driven individual with the capacity to adapt and learn fast. Excellent time management. I have excellent communication skills and ability to multi-task and work in a fast-paced environment. Have a creative approach and passion for work. I am an outstanding and conscientious team player, who is willing to learn new skills. I possess a positive attitude and have experience working in diverse environments.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Georgia Piedmont Technical College, Clarkston, GA

Associate Degree in Applied Science: Computer Support Specialist (2018) Help Desk Specialist Certificate (April 2018) PC Repair and Network Technician Certificate (July 2017) CompTIA A+ Certified Technician Preparation Certificate (Dec 2017)

#### **Udemy**

Web Developer Bootcamp Certificate (March 2018) AngularJS Certificate (Nov 2017) Node JS Certificate (Nov 2017) Build a Real Time web app Certificate (Nov 2017)

## **Friends of Refugees**

Web Development Certificate (August 2017)

### **Ethiopian Civil Service University**

Transformational Leadership Development and Decision-Making Certificate (December 2013)

#### **SKILLS**

- Web Development
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- iQuery
- Node.js
- Expres.js
- Frameworks
- GitHub

- Cross-browser development
- Git
- Chrome Inspector
- Coding tools
- Debugging tools
- FTP
- Web Hosting
- Knowledge about computer hardware and software

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance Web Developer and IT Consultant Clarkston, GA 2016 - present

- Extensive experience in developing websites and applications using latest web technologies.
- Extensive experience in responsive design using CSS3 and Bootstrap.
- Developed responsive websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (Sample: https://sintu.ga)
- Design, Develop, Review/Analyze, and modify programming systems including coding, testing, debugging and documenting programs.
- Experience with Bootstrap CSS framework, Node.js, Expres.js.
- Utilized creative and analytical problem-solving and troubleshooting skills
- Worked on Cross-Browser compatibility and fixed the bugs for several browsers.
- Troubleshoot coding errors and clean up the code on existing pages
- Installed and updated software with a package manager.
- Troubleshoot personal, family and friend's computers
- Installed and configure software
- Network peripheral devices

### Customer Service Rep/Cashier Dekalb Farmers Market – Decatur, GA 2015 –2017

- Exhibited professionalism and effective verbal and written communication skills to enhance customer experience
- Navigate file and folder structure, and created customer data
- Updated customer information in the customer service database
- Provided information on procedures or policies

- Calculated total payments received and reconciled this with total sales
- Performed quick math calculations when collecting payments

# **Relation Officer and School Coordinator** Communication Affairs and Education Office – Ethiopia 2007 – 2015

- Created the organization website and shared for other users
- Maintained and updated information on the organization's website
- Documented 400 teachers and 34 school's data in the organization database
- Created and modified tables entered and maintained data in the database
- Coordinated, organized and managed several events of the office
- Identified, analyzed and solved problems of schools, teachers, and supervisors
- Developed personal and the organization annual plan.
- Assisted in the development of plans and reports of the office
- Analyzed and evaluated the function of agencies and organizations and their impact on international relations